LAHIRU RAMESH

Full stack developer

+46 76 961 9007 | lahirusl.dev@gmail.com | Gothenburg, Sweden

LinkedIn | Github

Professional Summary

I have been a software engineer for over seven years. I excel in leading, designing, and developing successful projects, as well as in problem-solving. I enjoy learning new technologies and possess a blend of technical and interpersonal skills. My primary objective is to deliver secure, reliable, high-quality products with clean code.

Technical Skills

Programming	Artificial	Front-end	Backend Development & Databases	DevOps &
Languages	Intelligence	Development		Cloud
PythonTypescriptJavascriptJavaPHPC++	TensorFlowGen AIAgentic AIMachine Learning	 ReactJs NextJs VueJs Flutter Cypress Tailwindcss HTML5/Css3 	 NodeJs NestJs Django Spring MySQL PostgreSQL MongoDB 	 GitHub actions Docker Kubernetes Serverless Jenkins CI/CD AWS Google Cloud Kafka Terraform

Work Experience

Full-stack Developer (Remote/Part-time) - Nature preserve (06/2023 – 12/2024)

- Contributed as a Data Engineer to develop an Al-powered assistant that predicts the lowest carbon emission strategies for clients' product supply chains.
- Refactored "climate-impact-calculator" codebase to enhance cleanliness, and scalability by reducing average response time from 8 seconds to under 500 milliseconds.
- Played a key role as a Full Stack Developer in an innovative drawing tool for mapping the entire supply chain, streamlining supplier and client onboarding, and enabling seamless data sharing to simplify supplier data collection.
- Developed and documented authentication, authorization, tenant and user management for a multi-tenant web application to streamline the onboarding process for companies and their subsidiaries.

Senior Software Engineer (Remote/Full-time) - Eyepax IT Consulting (01/2023 – 04/2024)

- Engaged as a full-stack engineer in building a comprehensive platform for real estate agencies to centralize the management of real estate agreements across all Australian states, streamlining operations.
- Developed unit tests and Cypress end-to-end tests for each workflow, ensuring the delivery of a high-quality product for end users.

• Contributed as a full-stack engineer to the re-architecture with event sourcing to simplify creating and managing real estate agreements.

Associate Technical Lead - InsureMe Digital Services (01/2020 – 01/2023)

- Led a team of 7 members in the engineering department to establish long-term company goals.
- Supervised the development of outsourced teams to achieve cost savings and create room for growth.
- Acquired cybersecurity certifications from vendors to enhance the security of products.
- Managed the development of four SaaS products, guiding each from MVP to onboarding over 3 clients.
- Configured Jenkins, CI/CD pipelines and monitoring tools for each SaaS product in both internal and client cloud environments, enabling fast delivery and centralized visibility of all products.
- Collaborated closely with clients and vendors to establish processes between products and clients, optimising and streamlining operations.

Software Engineer - InsureMe Digital Services (08/2018 – 01/2020)

- Led the revamp of the website and internal apps, resulting in a 12.1% annual sales growth in 2018.
- Mentored junior developers to continue product development and provide operational support.
- Served in a DevOps role to expedite the development of new products and maintain existing developments.

Associate Software Engineer - InsureMe Digital Services (09/2017 – 07/2018)

- Developed SSO auth application which provided access to all internal applications.
- Integrated insurance premium calculators to the Aggregator system.

Education

Postgraduate Diploma in Enterprise Application Development (<u>Sri Lanka Institute of Information Technology</u>) (07/2021 – 01/2023)

Courses: Enterprise Software Architecture, Enterprise Mobility, Enterprise Software Analysis and design, Distributed Computing, Artificial Intelligence, Machine Learning, DevOps, IoT

Bachelor of Science (University of Colombo, Sri Lanka) (01/2014 – 01/2017)

Courses: Computer Science, Mathematics and Statistics

Language

Swedish (Learning)English(Fluent)

Interests

Run marathon
 Drawing
 Play chess
 Play cricket/carrom

References

References are available upon request.